SOFTWARE ENGINEER · BACK-END DEVELO New Taipei Citv. Taiwan

Summary _

Skilled Sr.Back-End Engineer at a global VR company with 4+ years of hands-on experience in back-end development, microservices & containerization, and software architecture areas with a willingness to learn and practice back-end architecture design and development. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools.

Skills

Programming Languages Golang, C/C++, Python, Node.js, Shell Script, JavaScript

Back-end MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Docker, AWS, Chef Habitat, Jenkins

Front-end React

Others Vim, Git, Mac OS X, Linux

Work Experience

HTC Vive / Viveport

New Taipei City, Taiwan

SENIOR BACKEND ENGINEER

Sep. 2020 - Now

- Designed and implemented a distributed audio recording system for the metaverse platform to record and store audio data from multiple sources.
- Designed and implemented user accounts management service by integrating APIs with a cloud hosting third-party service as a part of the
 multi-platform SaaS product to standardize the way of user accounts management amongst different projects and mitigating code duplicity.
- Recommend, introduce and migrate to a high-performance asynchronous web framework to reduce 85% micro-services API response time.
- Participating in building and deploying overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, CDN, and several AWS stacks (including EC2, EKS, MongoDB, RDS, Route 53, S3, Lambda, and CloudWatch), focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Designed and implemented the 99.99% up-time RESTful APIs for the critical multi-platform application with over 90% unit test coverage, which
 provided a critical connectivity channel for distributed functionality and kept manageable code complexity with micro-services architecture.

InfoBoom Ltd.

New Taipie City, Taiwan

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2020 - Sep. 2020

Dec. 2016 - Jun. 2018

- Responsible for refactoring the existing WebRTC server infrastructure from monolithic to microservice to improve scalability and reduce cost.
- Responsible for the improvement of the core cryptography library of the instant messaging SaaS product with a higher security level to be fully ISO27001 compliant and Taiwan MAS compliant.
- Recommended, introduced and built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on GitLab for the business-critical multi-platform cryptography library using Docker, resulting in a 3x reduction of average deployment time.

Synology Taipei, Taiwan

PRODUCT DEVELOPER

• Developed new features for the mail server application in C/C++. Resulting in 10+ releases delivered just in time.

- Designed and developed new features for the mail server application to be GDPR compliant and data privacy compliance.
- Coordinated with engineering and product teams in the identification of customer requirements and development of new features for the mail

server application.

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

RESEARCH ASSISTANT May. 2014 - Aug. 2014

Education _

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

M.S. OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2014 - June. 2016

• Thesis: Time-Sensitive Message Delivering with QoS in Named Data Networking

National Chiao Tung University

Hsinchu, Taiwan

B.S. of Computer Science Sep. 2008 - June. 2013

External Projects __

Video Converter

HTTPS://VIDEO-CONVERTER-RHO.VERCEL.APP/

Video Converter is a web application that converts videos from numerous websites to other formats.

FastAPI Backend Boilerplate

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/KLEE1611/COOKIECUTTER-FASTAPI-MONGO

FastAPI Backend Boilerplate is a cookiecutter template for creating a FastAPI backend with MongoDB, including testing and Docker support.